(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-07-31T05:48:58.818227",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
あたしタランちゃま！クモ人間なの！
I'm Taranchama! A spider-human!
お前を食っちゃうぞ～！
I'm gonna eat you up!
ふふふ！だめだよ～！
Hehehe! No way~!
ずってみんな、なかよし！
We'll be best friends forever!
うふふ、やくそくだよ♪
Hehehe, it's a promise♪
あなたは今どこで何をしているですか
Where are you right now and what are you doing?
この空の続く場所にいますか
Are you in the place where this sky continues?
今まで私の心を埋めていたもの
What had filled my heart until now,
失って初めて気付いた
I realized only after losing it,
こんなにも私を支えてくれていたこと
How much you had supported me,
こんなにも笑顔をくれていたこと
And how many smiles you had given me.
失ってしまった代償は
The price of losing it all
とてつもなく大きすぎて
Is far too immense,
取り戻そうと必死に
As I desperately tried to take it back,
手を伸ばしてもがくけれど
I reach out my hands and struggle, yet
迷って風のようにすり抜けて届きそうで届かない
Lost, slipping away like the wind, almost reaching you yet out of reach.
孤独と絶望に胸を締め付けられ
My chest squeezed tight by loneliness and despair,
心が壊れそうになるけれど
My heart feels like it's about to break, but
想い出に残るあなたの笑顔が
Your smile remaining in my memories
私をいつも励ましてくれる
Always encourages me.
もう一度あの頃に戻ろう
Let's return to those days once more.
今度はきっと大丈夫
This time, it'll surely be okay.
いつも側で笑っていよう
Let's always laugh by each other's side.
あなたのすぐ側で
Right by your side.
あなたは今どこで何をしているですか
Where are you right now and what are you doing?
あなたは今どこで何をしていますか？
Where are you now and what are you doing?
この空の続く場所にいますか？
Are you in the place where the sky continues?
いつものように笑顔でいてくれますか？
Can you keep smiling as usual?
グッズ販売のお知らせ！！
Merchandise sale announcement!
家族写真B2タペストリー
Family Photo B2 Tapestry
ゴージャスな額縁デザインと肖像画のような二人がとってもキュート。
Gorgeous frame design and the two looking like a portrait are so cute.
お部屋の壁に、今日の思い出を飾って彩り豊かな推し活ができちゃいます！
Decorate your room's wall with today's memories to enjoy colorful oshi-katsu!
おでかけちゃまぬいぐるみ
Outing-Chama Plushie
ボタン風の目がとっても可愛いぬいぐるみ！
A plushie with very cute button-like eyes!
丁寧にひとつひとつ再現されたドレス衣装のちゃまと一緒におでかけして旅に出れちゃいます！
You can go on a trip and outing together with Chama in her faithfully recreated dress outfit!
鞄に付けれるハートチャーム付き！
Includes a heart charm that can be attached to bags!
タランちゃまぬいぐるみポーチ
Taran-Chama Plushie Pouch
あのタランちゃまがポーチに！
That Taran-Chama is now a pouch!
背中のファスナーが開いて収納できる便利アイテム、ゴスロリ衣装のタランちゃまが可愛すぎる！
A convenient item with a zipper on the back for storage, Taran-Chama in her gothic Lolita outfit is too cute!
チェーンがついているから安心して御外にお散歩させられるよ！
It has a chain so you can safely take her out for a walk!
タランちゃまスマホリング
Taran-Chama Smartphone Ring
スマホの落下は「タランちゃま」にお任せ！
Leave smartphone drops to 'Taran-Chama'!
しっかり張り付いて守ってくれます！
She clings tightly to protect it!
愛くるしいお目目と、つい目が合っちゃう瞬間も癒されてたまりません。
You can't help being healed by her adorable eyes and those moments when your eyes meet.
全部セットは数量限定もあります！
There is also a limited quantity for the all-in-one set!
フルセット購入特典の数量限定ver.は、赤井はあと直筆サイン＆箔押し複製メッセージ入りポストカードと直筆サイン特典ボイス「ひみつの話し」もあるよ！プロモカードもあるよ！
The limited quantity Full Set purchase bonus includes a postcard with Akai Haato's duplicated foil-stamped signature and message, signed voice 'Secret Talk', and a promo card!
hololive公式ECサイトへGO！！
Go to the hololive official EC site!!
ひとつだけ、ただひとつだけ 見つけたものは
The only thing, just the only thing I found
誠実で不器用な、それでも柔らかな声 朽ちてゆき、ただ崩れゆく、世界を照らす
is a sincere, clumsy, yet soft voice illuminating a world that decays and collapses.
暖かで、でも残酷な、去り際の笑顔 ひび割れてく翡翠の水槽を満たしたもの
A warm yet cruel parting smile, filling a cracked jade water tank.
「永遠ではない」なんて、初めから解ってたのに…
Even though I knew from the start that it wouldn't last forever...
壊れても、なお美しく、胸を刻むのは
What etches into my heart, still beautiful even when broken,
砕けても、なお美しい、ひとひらの記憶
is a single fragment of memory, still beautiful even when shattered.
忘れたいのに、なお狂おしく、胸に残るのは
And what remains in my heart, even more madly when I want to forget it,
痛みさえ忘れさせた、微かな感触
is a faint tactile sensation that made me forget even the pain.
ひとつだけ、ただひとつだけ 伝えたのは
The only thing, just the only thing I conveyed
冷たさで誤魔化した、苦し紛れの嘘
was a desperate lie masked by coldness.
愛して、ただ愛して、選んだ言葉は
The words I chose, loving you, just loving you,
すべて終わらせる偽りのセリフ
were a false line to end everything.
風が吹けば飛ぶような砂に残した手紙 「永遠ではない」ということも忘れられたのに…
A letter left in the sand, easily blown away by the wind... even though I had forgotten that 'it's not forever'...
「永遠ではない」ということさえ忘れられたのに…
"Even though I had forgotten that it wasn't forever..."
もう一度、もう一度と、もう何度思ったでしょう
How many times, over and over, must I have thought it?
枯れた花束、捨てられもせず
Unable to even throw away the withered bouquet,
降り止まぬ雨は、まるで万雷の拍手喝采
The ceaseless rain is like a thunderous ovation,
愚かな後悔を 嘲笑う怒濤のよう
like surging waves mocking foolish regrets.
壊れても、なお美しく、胸を刻むのは
What etches into my heart, still beautiful even when broken,
砕けても、なお美しい、ひとひらの記憶
is a single petal of memory, still beautiful even when shattered.
忘れたいのに、なお狂おしく、胸に残るのは
Even though I want to forget, what still lingers madly in my chest
痛みさえ忘れさせた、微かな感触
is a faint sensation that made me forget even the pain.
微かな感触
A faint sensation...
What's more, what's more, play your little game
Faces identical, bodies the same
「なんで、いなくなっちゃったの…」
"Why did you disappear..."
「こんなの苦しいよ…」
"This is so painful..."
「そばにいて…」
"Stay by my side..."
If you promised me
「いつも、そばにいるよ。」
"I'll always be by your side."
もう忘れてしまったかな
I wonder if you've already forgotten
夏の木陰に座ったまま、アイスを口に放り込んで風を待っていた
Sitting in the summer shade, eating ice cream and waiting for the breeze.
もう忘れてしまったかな、世の中の全部嘘だらけ
I wonder if you've forgotten, that the world is full of lies.
本当の価値を二人で探しに行こうと笑ったこと
And how we laughed about going together to search for true value.
忘れないように、色褪せないように
So we won't forget, so it won't fade away,
形に残るものが全てじゃないように
so that physical things aren't all that remains.
言葉をもっと教えて
Teach me more words,
夏が来るって教えて
teach me that summer is coming.
僕らは描いている、目に映るのは夏の亡霊
We are drawing it; what's reflected in my eyes is a summer ghost.
風にスカートが揺れて
My skirt sways in the wind,
想い出なんて忘れて、浅い呼吸をする、汗を拭いて夏めく
forgetting memories, taking shallow breaths, wiping sweat as summer deepens.
もう忘れてしまったかな
I wonder if you've already forgotten
夏の木陰に座った頃、遠くの丘から顔出した雲があったじゃないか
When we sat in the summer shade, wasn't there a cloud peeking out from a distant hill?
もう忘れてしまったかな
I wonder if you've already forgotten
夏の木陰に座った頃、遠くの丘から顔出した雲があったじゃないか
When we sat in the summer shade, wasn't there a cloud peeking out from a distant hill?
君はそれを掴もうとして、バカみたいに空を切った手で
You tried to grasp it, with your hand foolishly slicing through the empty sky,
僕は紙に雲一つを描いて、笑って握って見せて
while I drew a single cloud on paper, smiling, holding it out to show you.
忘れないように、色褪せないように
So we won't forget, so it won't fade away,
歴史に残るものが全てじゃないから
because historical records aren't all that remains.
今だけ顔も失くして
Forgetting even our faces for now,
言葉も全部忘れて、君は笑ってる、夏を待って
forgetting all words, you are smiling, waiting for summer.
もう忘れてしまったかな
I wonder if I've already forgotten...
心をもっと教えて
Tell me more about your heart,
夏の匂いを教えて
tell me the scent of summer,
浅い呼吸をする
and I take a shallow breath.
忘れないように
So I won't forget,
色褪せないように
so it won't fade away,
心に響くものが全てじゃないから
because not everything that echoes in the heart is all there is.
言葉をもっと教えて
Tell me more words,
さよならだって教えて
tell me even what "goodbye" means.
今も見るんだよ 夏に咲いて散る花に亡霊を
I still see them now—ghosts blooming in the summer flowers—
言葉じゃなくて時間を
time, not words;
時間じゃなくて心を 浅い呼吸をする
heart, not time, as I take a shallow breath.
汗をぬぐって夏めく
Wiping away sweat as summer approaches,
夏の匂いがする
I catch the scent of summer.
The scent of summer lingers.
もう忘れてしまったかな 夏の木陰に座ったまま
I wonder if I've already forgotten, sitting in the summer shade,
アイスを口に放り込んで風を待っていた
throwing ice cream into my mouth and waiting for the breeze.
ということで！赤井はあと爆誕祭2025始まっちゃうよ！
And so! Akai Haato's Birth Fest 2025 is starting right now!
おお、事故事故事故！あぶな、あぶな！
Whoa, crash, crash, crash! Watch out, watch out!
危ない危ない危ない！1曲目、1曲目まだ！
Careful, careful, careful! First song isn't over yet!
体勢保存しないと！
We gotta maintain our posture!
え、ゲストに来てくれたのはラレンちゃん！
Um, the guest who came to join us is Raren-chan!
こんばんは！ホロライブデベロップメントインドネシアの10期生ラレンでございます！
Good evening! I'm Raren from Hololive Dev_is Indonesia!
ありがとうございます来てくださって！
Thank you so much for coming!
誕生日おめでとうございます！ありがとうございます！
Ha-chan, happy birthday! - Thank you so much!
そして新衣装じゃないですか！
And what's more, that's a new outfit, isn't it?!
そうなんだよ！すらーっとならならなら…綺麗！可愛い！
That's right! So sleek and stylish... Gorgeous! Cute!
いや、この衣装めっちゃシナジーある！
Man, this outfit has amazing synergy!
あ、あれあれ？これクリスマスカラーだね、二人とも！そうなの！
Wait, hold on? These are Christmas colors for both of us!
だってほらクリスマスツリー、さ、はーちゃんは…
Because look, a Christmas tree, and Ha-chan is...
サンタ！サンタ！サンタです！サンタね、この季節にぴったり…
Santa! Santa! I'm Santa! Perfect for this season...
サンタね、この季節にぴったり、んー…
Santa, perfect for this season, hmm...
おっ、ぴったりですね、夏を、夏の匂いが…夏って追加して！
Oh, it's so fitting—the scent of summer... Add summer in there!
クリスマスだと思ってたんだよ！
I thought it was Christmas!
だからね、えっと、はーちゃん、じゃあはーちゃんじゃない、赤井はと
So you see, um, Ha-chan—well, not Ha-chan, Akai Haato...
爆誕祭2025でね、是非ともSNSでスクショとかツイートしてください！
At the Birth Fest 2025, please tweet with screenshots!
じゃあなんか写真撮ろっか！
Shall we take some photos then?
撮りましょう！おしとやかなポーズいきますか？せっかくなんで！
Let's take some! Shall we go with an elegant pose?
じゃあ、おしとやかに、がっつりとね！がっつり！
Alright, nice and elegant, fully committed!
決めポーズ！おしとやかなポーズ！ありじゃない？ホロライブ！
Strike a pose! An elegant pose! Isn't that great? Hololive!
はっ！強さ！強さしかねえ！最強！最強！やったー！
Ha! Strength! Nothing but strength! The strongest! Yay!
え、じゃあどうしようかな？あ、ちょっとハートを、いまどきなハートで！
Um, what should we do? Ah, let's make a modern heart shape!
ハートで、いいんじゃないすか？あ、かわいい！
With a heart, isn't that nice? Ah, so cute!
ハート！ふふっ
Heart! Heh.
ああー！あはははは！
Ahhh! Hahaha!
いいよ、いいよ！ラレンちゃんもいいよ！戻ってきて、戻ってきて！
That's good! Raren-chan, that's good too! Come back!
あ、うちらの中じゃなくないすか？
Wait, isn't this inside of us?
ホロライブ！あぶないあぶない！あ、やばいやばい！
Hololive! Watch out! Oh no!
今の、ね、今の勝つ入れただけだから！
That was just me putting Katsu in!
まあまあまあ、そんな殴ったりとかしないからね、別に！
Well, it's not like we're gonna beat each other up!
しっとりした曲の後ですから！
After all, that was after such an emotional song!
みんなスクショ撮ってくれてるか？撮ってくれてるかな？
Is everyone taking screenshots? Are you guys?
楽しんでるぞー！まあ、そんなわけで！
We're having fun! Well, with that being said!
今回ですね、我々は、なんかホロライブ、そうですよ、我々ユニット名ホロライブですから！
This time, we are... right, because we're the Hololive unit!
覚えてくださいね！いつの間にかできてた…ホロライブ、という感じでラレンちゃんをお迎えさせてもらいました！
Please remember that! And so we welcomed Raren-chan!
ありがとー！
Thank you!
ございますー。してね、あの衣装もシナジーがあるってことで、
...Good evening! Also, our outfits have good synergy,
え、花に亡霊をね歌ったんですけども、どうでした？
um, we sang "Ghost in a Flower," how was it?
えもう
Oh man...
いやもうこのステージすっごいあってたし、
No, this stage fit it so well!
いや、やっぱね、あのラヴェンクロフトに歌ってほしいパートがあったんですよ、やっぱ。
And you know, there was a part I really wanted Ravencroft to sing.
あの、歴史に残るものだけが全てじゃないってところで、
Like, things that go down in history aren't everything,
あ、これちょっとラヴェンクロフトに歌ってほしいなと思って、掛け合いをお願いさせてもらいました。
so I thought I'd love for Ravencroft to sing this, and asked for a duet.
うれしい。
I'm so happy.
いや、でもどっかで歌いたいなっていう
I was like, I wanted to sing together somewhere...
あ、そうなんだ。よかった。
Oh, is that so? I'm glad.
いや、この曲一緒に歌いたいんだって言ってくれた時、え、めっちゃ嬉しいと思って、よかった！嬉しい！
When you said you wanted to sing this song together, I was so happy!
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much!
じゃあ、じゃあ待って、帰ってね。
Well then, wait, let's go back.
こっから？こっから？え？うわ
From here? From here? Eh? Whoa!
じゃ、じゃ、ほら！
Now, now, look!
ほら、これから頑張ってください！
Look, do your best from here on!
ありがとー！
Thank you!
頑張って頑張って！これどうやって帰るの？
Do your best! How do we go back?
あ、違う、あ、じゃあこっち？
Ah, wait, is it this way?
あ、そっか、こっちとかあるんだ、こういうのって。あっぶな。
Oh right, there are paths like this. That was close.
じゃ、ありがとー！
Well then, thanks!
頑張ってくださーい！
Do your best!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
はるか 遠い 遠い 昔 巻かれた 首輪
A collar wound around from a distant, distant past.
人が欲しい 人が欲しいと叫ぶ 呪いの首輪
A cursed collar crying, "I want someone, I want someone."
怒らないで 見捨てないで どこにもいかないで (ねえ)
Don't get angry, don't abandon me, don't go anywhere (Hey)
強く 締める 吐くまで 締める 人がいない いない と
Tighten it hard, tighten it until I vomit, because there's no one here.
いい成績でしょ ねえ ねえ いい子でしょ 可愛い子でしょ ねえ ねえ 良い子でしょう 苦しい ねぇ
I have good grades, right? Hey, I'm a good girl, right? A cute girl, right? Hey, a good child, right? It hurts, hey.
強く 締める 悪魔で 締める 人がいない いない と
Tighten it strongly, tighten it like a demon, because there's no one, no one here.
ええぜ? さきでしょ ねぇ ねぇ いいこでしょ かわいいこでしょ
Isn't it great? Ahead, right? Hey, hey, a good child, right? A cute child, right?
ねぇ ねぇ いいこでしょ 苦しい ねぇ
Hey, hey, a good child, right? It hurts, hey.
いいこでしょ 苦しい ねぇ
A good child, right? It hurts, hey.
愛して 愛して 愛して もっともっと
Love me, love me, love me, more and more!
愛して 愛して 狂おしい ほど に
Love me, love me, to the point of madness!
苦しい ほどに 苦しい 苦しい 縛りを 解いて 解いて ねえ
So painfully, so painfully, unbind this painful restriction, hey!
止められない ah
I can't stop it, ah...
体 体 大きくなっても 小さい 首輪
Even if my body grows big, my neck is still small.
苦しくなる 足りなくなる 人が 人が 足りない
It gets painful, it's not enough, there aren't enough people, people!
クラスの 誰にも負けない キレイな いい子でしょ (ねえ)
A clean, good girl who loses to no one in class, right? (Hey)
どの子よりも どの女の子よりも 誰も彼も私を見てよ
Look at me more than any girl, than any other girl, everyone, anyone!
体育館裏 あなたに告白を 嘘みたいでしょ
Behind the gymnasium, my confession to you... It sounds like a lie, right?
あなたが好き な 汚いあなたが
I love you... you dirty person.
あなたが 好きなの 汚い あなたが
You are the one I love, you dirty person!
愛して 愛して 愛して 全部あげる
Love me, love me, love me, I'll give you everything!
あなたに あなたに 全部しょって もらうよ
I'll make you, make you carry it all on your shoulders!
足りない あなたが 足りない 離さないよ ah - ah
You're not enough, you're not enough, I won't let you go, ah-ah!
愛して 愛して 愛して もっともっと
Love me, love me, love me, more and more!
愛して 愛して 狂おしい ほど に
Love me, love me, to the point of madness!
苦しい ほどに 苦しい 叶わない 苦しい もっともっと ねえ
So painfully, so painfully unfulfilled, painful, more and more, hey!
幸せ な の ah 幸せ な の ah
I'm so happy, ah... I'm so happy, ah...
はるか遠い遠い昔 巻かれた首輪
Far, far away, long ago, a wrapped collar...
人が欲しい 人が欲しいと叫ぶ呪いの首輪
The cursed collar screaming "I want someone, I want someone!"
Yeah! Let's go!
Oh, it's heavy! Okay, let's try! Okay, let's go!
I feel so 努力未来 A BEAUTIFUL STAR
I feel so hard work, future, A BEAUTIFUL STAR
あーいのせっせっせー あー、what what I do? チェンソー
Ah, love's 1-2-3, ah, what what I do? Chainsaw
あー、いーてー！ あー、いや！ あー、いーてー！
Ah, it hurts! Ah, no! Ah, it hurts!
愛して愛して愛して 欲しそうない
Love me, love me, love me, wanting so much
We are living together! Yeah! And also...
Happy Birthday! Happy Birthday! Yay, it's really nice birthday today!
Happy Birthday! Happy Birthday! Yay, it's a really nice birthday today!
Thank you for letting us celebrate it with you! Thanks for inviting us!
It's so fun! Yeah! Ah yeah yeah...
Oh, it's the first time to we I can some we did uh the glue. Oh yeah!
Oh, it's the first time we... I can do some... we did the glue! Oh yeah!
Ina and Marine and Hachama, we are... Happy Birthday Hachama!
Happy Birthday Hachama! Just make it! We just jumbled our names together! Happy Birthday Hachama! Let's take a picture!
Oh, okay. Okay, okay. Everyone takes a picture!
Dangerous! Dangerous!
Let's... let's kill them!
A camera? Yeah, camera! Sayonara! Sayonara!
Happy Birthday Haato!
ねえ 私知ってるよ 君がひとり
Hey, I know it, you're all alone...
知ってるの 知ってるよ
I know, I know it!
くすんくすんでこもってさ 夜の人からいんじゃない
Sobbing and depressed in the night, aren't you?
朝が来るまで一緒 歌うもっと泣いたって
Singing together until morning, crying even more...
普通普通 恥ずかしいみんな隠しているだけ もっと
Just normal, just embarrassed, everyone's hiding it, more and more!
ねえ 私知ってるよ 君がひとりの見出し
Hey, I know it, your solitary headline...
知ってるの 知ってるよ
I know, I know it!
ぐすんぐすんヘコんでさ 悪い人からいいんじゃない
Sobbing and depressed, isn't it better from a bad person?
朝が来るまで一緒 感想もっと泣いたってなんのくだっても
Together until morning, thoughts, crying even more, whatever it is...
受け止めてあげる もうがまんしないでいっぱい出してね
I'll accept it all, don't hold back anymore, let it all out!
お願い 君がほしいの 慰めさせて シェイクシェイク
Please, I want you, let me comfort you, shake, shake!
愛の才能で 泣いてくれなきゃ 痺れてしまう 濡れていたい
With the talent of love, if you don't cry, I'll go numb, I want to stay soaked.
ねえ いいでしょ 舐め取って 飲み干したいんだってば
Hey, isn't that fine? I want to lick it off, drink it all up!
お願い 君がほしいの 頼り散らして シックラブなんて最高ね
Please, I want you, lean on me completely, sick love is the best!
分け合ってくれなきゃ 君の「痛い」感じていたい 覗いていたい
If you don't share, I want to feel your 'pain', I want to peek at it.
吸い取って 救いたいんだってば
I want to suck it dry and save you!
わけてもくれなきゃ 君の痛い 出してだなんて
If you don't share, asking to let your pain out...
ねえ いいでしょ 吸い取って 救いたいんだってば
Hey, isn't that fine? I want to suck it dry and save you!
ねえ 私知ってるよ 君がひとり気にしてんの
Hey, I know it, you're worrying all alone.
知ってるよ ずくんずくん高まるじゃん 君を押すことはやめない
I know, throbbing high, I won't stop pushing you.
ねえ 私知ってるよ 君をやれるか知ってるよ
Hey, I know it, I know if I can do you.
つらいときは 弱いくらいでちょうどいい 私それでも好きだよ
When it's tough, being a bit weak is just right, I love you even like that.
お願い 君がほしいの 名前を呼んでよ いつだって会いに参上
Please, I want you, call my name, I'll come see you anytime.
きみはひとりだだから歌う「ひとりじゃない」
You're all alone, that's why I sing 'you're not alone'.
もういいでしょう そのプレイはおしまいなんだってば
That's enough now, that play is over!
きみが病めるときもあたし側にいるわ いつも見守っているわ
Even when you fall sick, I'm by your side, always watching over you.
そうよ 怖くないのよ あたしそばにいるわ
That's right, don't be scared, I'm right by your side.
いつも見守っているわ そうよ怖くないのよ
Always watching over you, that's right, don't be scared.
お願い 君が欲しいの
Please, I want you
慰めさせてシェイク シェイク 愛の才能で
Let me comfort you, shake, shake, with the talent of love
泣いてくれなきゃ 壊れてしまう
If you don't cry for me, I'll break down
笑ってないで 知ってるでしょ 舐めたての身が欲しいの
Don't just smile, you know it, I want a freshly tasted body
1, 2, 3とたっぱ
1, 2, 3 and...
お願い 君が欲しいの
Please, I want you
手を伸ばしてしっくら
Reach out your hand, shikkura
なんて最高ね
How wonderful that is
ほっぺた触ってよ 君の痛い 感じてたい 添い寝したい
Touch my cheek, I want to feel your pain, I want to sleep with you
吸い取って すくい取って
Sucking it up, scooping it up
1, 2, 3とたっぱ
1, 2, 3 and...
新しいセオリーを 君の知らん話しての 知ってよ
Tell me the new theory you don't know, know it
ずぶずぶ吸い込んで 最後は人からいただくない
Sucking deep in, in the end receiving from others
朝が来るまで 一緒かすも とまったって
Until morning comes, let's stay together, even if it stops
何度だって 受け止めてあげる
No matter how many times, I will catch you
まだまだ失えないから ステップステップトッパー
Still can't lose it, step, step, topper
諦めの悪い野郎からオントンノーナ 隅っこで踊るのも大概にしとけ
From the stubborn jerks, oonton nona, stop dancing in the corner already
クワバラ、クワバラ、クワバラ 目にもの見舞う速さ
Kuwabara, kuwabara, kuwabara, with blinding speed
クタバラン ダマラン サガラン 押し通すわがまま
Cut 'em down, shut 'em down, push 'em down, forcing your selfishness through
そこどきなジャマだ 俺はもう一人のあなた
Move aside, you're in the way, I am the other you
サダちゃん カヤちゃん わんさか夜の国ワンダーランド
Sada-chan, kaya-chan, swarming into the land of the night, wonderland
ごきとちゅうに なんだか 四時、四分、四十分まわったら
In the middle of gokichuu, running around at 4:44
よっしゃ 四尺、四寸、四分 ざまが神立っちゃう
Alright, 4 shaku, 4 sun, 4 fun, as if the wrath of God is coming down
バンアラウンド、ヘイ 呼ぶ声がしたなら 文面通りお疲れ様やん
Bang around, hey, when you hear a voice calling out, it's literally time to say otsukaresan yan
闇からのサラバ、ヘイ 飛び立っていく彼方、ヘイ
Goodbye from the darkness, hey, flying off to distant lands, hey
心身体頭 懐かしい温かさ 足元に今花が咲いたならば
My heart, body, and head feel the nostalgic warmth, if flowers have blossomed at our feet now
闇からのサラバ、ヘイ 飛び立っていく彼方、ウー
Goodbye from the darkness, hey, flying off to distant lands, woah!
何度だって生きる おまえや君の中
Living over and over again, inside you or me
まぶたの裏や耳の中 胃の奥にいつづける
Behind your eyelids or inside your ears, staying deep within your stomach
メロディ リズムに、Yeah...
Into the melody and rhythm, yeah...
今日も細胞の数まで積み上げてく top of top
Today too, piling up to the number of cells, top of top
鬼とチャンバラ the lyrical chainsaw massacre
Sword fighting with ogres, the lyrical chainsaw massacre
渡る大海原 花歌歌いしゃらら
Crossing the open sea, singing alone with a sha-la-la
払いたいのなら 末代までの札束
If you want to pay, bundles of cash that last forever
誰が開けたかパンドラ あとは何があっても知らんがな
Who opened Pandora's box? I don't care what happens next
何百年待たが 超久しぶりの娑婆だ
How many hundreds of years have I waited? It's been so long since I've been in the world
ガキや若葉 まだこっち来んじねえよ馬鹿が
You kids and greenhorns, don't come over here yet, you idiots
今確かに目が合ったな こういうことかよシャマラン
Our eyes definitely met just now, is this what they mean, Shyamalan?
闇からのサラバ、ヘイ 飛び立っていく彼方、ヘイ
Goodbye from the darkness, hey, flying off to distant lands, hey
心身体頭 懐かしい温かさ 足元に今花が咲いたならば
My heart, body, and head feel the nostalgic warmth, if flowers have blossomed at our feet now
闇からのサラバ、ヘイ 飛び立っていく彼方、ヘイ
Goodbye from the darkness, hey, flying off to distant lands, hey
心身体頭 懐かしい温かさ 足元に今花が咲いたならば
My heart, body, and head feel the nostalgic warmth, if flowers have blossomed at our feet now
闇からのサラバ、ヘイ 飛び立っていく彼方、ヘイ
Goodbye from the darkness, hey, flying off to distant lands, hey
心身体頭 懐かしい温かさ 足元に今花が咲いたならば
My heart, body, and head feel the nostalgic warmth, if flowers have blossomed at our feet now
闇からのサラバ、ヘイ 飛び立っていく彼方、ウー
Goodbye from the darkness, hey, flying off to distant lands, woah!
何度だって生きる おまえや君の中
Living over and over again, inside you or me
まぶたの裏や耳の中 胃の奥にいつづける
Behind your eyelids or inside your ears, staying deep within your stomach
メロディ リズムに、Yeah...
Into the melody and rhythm, yeah...
お願い お願いよ こっちこないで
Please, please, don't come over here
ダメよ こころ乱さないで
No, don't disturb my heart
いつも いつもの いつもの はみ出さずに
Always, always, without stepping out of the lines
見本みたいに色を塗るばかり
Just coloring like the sample
すごく すごく 叫びたいのに
Even though I want to scream so much
今日もいい子になるわたしがいる
Today there is still a good girl inside me
すべて闇に染めよう 最初から黒なら悩まないだろう
"Let's dye everything in darkness. If it were black from the start, we wouldn't worry."
お願い お願いよ こっちこないで
Please, please, don't come over here
誰が決めたラインかわからないけれど
Even though I don't know who decided the lines
守っていなくちゃ不安になるの
I feel anxious unless I protect them
ダメよ こころ乱さないで
No, don't disturb my heart
爆誕ライブの途中ですが
We're in the middle of the birthday live, but
ここからはちょっと外に繰り出してロケをしていこうと思います
From here, we're going to step outside and do a location shoot
ここはですね…
This place is...
私が前から会いたかった方のご自宅ということなんですが
Today, I'm visiting the home of someone I've wanted to meet for a long time,
なんやらとんでもない雰囲気が漂ってます
but there's a really incredible atmosphere here...
この階段の先に…
Up ahead of these stairs...
オカルト界隈でも有名な呪物コレクターの方がいるはずなので
there should be a famous cursed item collector in the occult world,
早速突撃してみたいと思います
so I'm going to go pay them a sudden visit.
行きましょう、ドキドキ。
Let's go. I'm so nervous.
結構…階段の段差が…
Wow... these stairs are pretty steep...
うおぉぉ、めちゃ暗い。
Whoa... it's super dark.
一番奥のお部屋のはずなので、先に進んで行きましょう。
It should be the room at the very back, so let's keep going.
なんかスゴイ…異質ですね。
It has a really... bizarre vibe.
じゃあ、この…あ、この部屋なんですね。この一番奥の部屋のはずなので
So, this... oh, this is the room. It should be the room at the very back, so...
ちょっと…表札もないですが、一応ノックしてみますか?
There's no nameplate, but should I knock just in case?
トントン
*knock knock*
あれ…ここで合ってますかね? もう一度ノックしてみますか。
Huh... is this the right place? Let's try knocking once more.
はい。
Yes?
声が…
There's a voice...
あ…どうも。
Oh... hello.
あ、どうも。田中さんですか?
Ah, hello. Are you Mr. Tanaka?
はい。
Yes.
ホロライブ1期生の赤井はあとと申します。インタビュー撮影に来たんですが
I'm Akai Haato from Hololive 1st Generation. I'm here to do an interview shoot,
もし良かったら撮影…大丈夫ですか?
and if it's alright with you, can we... film?
大丈夫ですよ。
It's fine.
大丈夫ですか?
Is it really?
ありました。
We did.
あ、ありがとうございます。そうなんだ、約束してましたっけ?
Ah, thank you. Oh right, did we promise?
すいません。
Sorry.
忘れてました?
You forgot?
あ、ちょっと忘れてましたね。
Ah, I kinda forgot.
すすでに なんか… 色々見えてますけども 入ってもいいですか? はい お願いします。
I can already see various things... Is it okay if I come in? Yes, please.
お邪魔します。失礼しまーす。
Excuse me. Pardon me.
これ全部呪物なんですか?
Are all of these cursed items?
そうなんすね…あの、呪物というか、まぁ…呪われた…
That's right... well, rather than cursed items, well... cursed...
あ、呪われ…呪われちゃってるんだ。
Ah, they're... they've been cursed.
え、田中さんは大丈夫なんですか?
Eht, are you okay, Mr. Tanaka?
いやでもずっとしんどいっすよ。
Well, but I feel terrible all the time.
えぇ!?
Eh?!
え、全部ちゃんと呪われてる…？
Eh, so all of them are properly cursed...?
うん、そうすね。中にはまぁ…あの、良い物もありますけど。
Mm, that's right. Among them, well... there are some good things too.
あ、そうなんですね。呪いにも種類があるんですか?
Ah, is that so? Are there different types of curses?
ありますね。
There are.
ちなみに、今配信を見ている人たちのために、田中さんがどんな方なのか自己紹介してもらってもよろしいですか?
By the way, for the people watching the stream right now, could you introduce yourself and tell us what kind of person you are?
呪物コレクターの田中俊行です。よろしくお願いします。
I'm Toshiyuki Tanaka, a cursed item collector. Nice to meet you.
よろしくお願いします。
Nice to meet you too.
仕事は怪談師なんすよ。怖い話の仕事。
My job is a ghost story storyteller. Telling scary stories.
え、そうなんだ。
Eh, is that right?
趣味、ライフワークで…呪われたものを集めてる。
As a hobby and life's work... I collect cursed things.
じゃ、ちなみに、今田中さんが立ってる奥の部屋にも呪物があるんですか?
Well, by the way, are there cursed items in the back room where you're standing right now too?
そうなんすよ。元々こっちだけが呪物部屋だったんですけど、あ、そうなんですね。
That's right. Originally only this side was the cursed room, but ah, is that so?
量が入り切らなくなって、奥にも…入れたりするんですか?
The amount got too big to fit, so you put them in the back too?
奥入れますけど…奥は比較的
I put them in the back, but... the back is relatively
僕が個人的に契約してる呪物が多くて、入らない方がいい…
full of cursed items I've personally contracted with, so it's better not to go in...
入ったら危ない。うーん、あんましか…たぶん呪物が嫌がると思う。
It's dangerous to go in. Hmm, probably... the cursed items wouldn't like it.
あー、そういう感じなんだ。
Ah, I see how it is.
なんか一番最初にここ入って、一番気になったのが…
When I first came in here, the one I was most curious about...
あの、なんか赤いお面の横にある白いお面で、あれはどういう呪物なんですか?
Uh, is that white mask next to the red mask, what kind of cursed item is that?
あれは“呪いの面”って言われてて、こうつけたら不幸が訪れるって言われてるんですよ。
That's called the "Cursed Mask," and it's said that if you put it on, misfortune will befall you.
あ、そう。実際にそうやって不幸が起こっちゃった人もいるんですか?
Oh really? Are there actually people who put it on and had misfortunes happen to them?
います。京都の蓮久寺っていうお寺、そこに三木大雲さんっていう和尚がいるんですよ。その
Yes. There's a temple in Kyoto called Renkyu-ji, where there is a monk named Daiun Miki. From that
三木大雲さんから預かったもので、
monk Daiun Miki, I received it,
たぶんこれピーだと思いますけど、自主規制がつけたっていうんすよ。
and well, this is probably censored, but "self-censorship" put it on, they say.
え、つけたの!?
Eh, they put it on?!
なんでつけちゃったんですか? いや、そういう番組があったっていう。あ、試しにつけちゃえみたいなノリで。
Why did they go ahead and put it on? Well, there was a program like that, so... with the vibe of "let's try putting it on for fun."
がっつり呪われちゃいましたね…。
They got thoroughly cursed, huh...
ちゃんとに呪われてる…。
Properly cursed...
基本、お祓いが済んでないものが、ここでは普通です。
Basically, things that haven't been exorcised are normal here.
だから僕も、そういう呪物受け取る時に、あの、人を呪ったものとかありますけど、その「お祓いはやめてくれ」って言います。
So even when I receive such cursed items, uh, even if there are things that cursed people, I tell them, "Stop the exorcism."
珍しいw
That's rare lol
(お祓いすると)意味がなくなるので…
Because (doing an exorcism) makes it lose its meaning...
え、じゃあ、ちなみに田中さんおすすめの呪物ありますか?
Eh, then by the way, do you have any cursed items you recommend, Mr. Tanaka?
ありますあります。
I do, I do.
おおー！
Oooh!
じゃあちょっと持ってきますわ。
Well, I'll go get one.
持ってきてくれるんですね。
You're going to bring it for me.
お願いしま〜す！
Please do~!
お人形さんだ！
It's a doll!
お人形さん持ってきてくれた。
He brought a doll for me.
あ、奥の部屋…奥の部屋あれですよね? 契約の部屋ですけど…大丈夫なんですか…？危険な…
Ah, the back room... the back room is that one, right? The room of contracts, but... is it okay...? It's dangerous...
出せっていうから…
Because it told me to let it out...
あ、でも可愛い…可愛いなんかパジャマ着てる。
Ah, but it's cute... it's wearing cute pajamas.
ジェラピケ着てるんです。
It's wearing Gelato Pique.
え、ジェラピケじゃな…あ、やっぱジェラピケなんだ！
Eh, it's not Gelato Pique... ah, as I thought, it is Gelato Pique!
なんで、あの、お気に入りなんですか?
Why is it, um, your favorite?
あの、こう呪物を…
Well, like, when collecting cursed items...
呪物を集めるきっかけになった人形
The doll that sparked the collection of cursed items...
どういうきっかけで？
How did that start?
元々こう怪談ライブとかやってたら
Well, originally I used to do ghost story live shows,
お客さんがあの持って来るんですよね、その…相談、お祓いとかもできると思われてて
and customers would bring things in, thinking I could help them or do exorcisms.
ええ…w
Heh... w
お祓いとかもできると思われてて
People thought I could do exorcisms and stuff.
ちなみに、お名前はなんて？
By the way, what's its name?
チャーミー
Charmy.
チャーミーさん
Charmy?
関西のあの、ある介護施設にいたんですよ。
It was at a nursing facility in Kansai.
へえ、そうなんですね。
Oh, is that right?
で、こう…誰が持ってきたかスタッフの人もわからない…
And nobody—not even the staff—knew who brought it.
利用者の方が…特定の利用者の人が可愛がるんですよ、何故か。
For some reason, a specific resident would dote on it.
え、あ、へえ
Huh, oh, I see.
可愛がると、三日以内に亡くなるんです。
Whenever someone doted on it, they would die within three days.
えっ…それが5人続いたので
Eh... That happened to five people in a row,
あの…ちょっと気持ち悪い…5人も続いたんですね…
So... that's kind creepy... Five people in a row...?
なので一度ね、地下の倉庫に隠したんですよね。
So they hid it away in the basement storage once.
隠されちゃったんだ
They hid it?
でも次の日には出てきてた…
But the next day, it reappeared.
ちゃんと脱出してる…w
It successfully escaped... w
スタッフの人が僕のこと知ってて…田中さんに預けようということで、持ってきてくれたんです。
The staff knew about me, so they brought it to me to entrust it to Tanaka-san.
で、バタバタしてたんで僕そのまま…中身見ずに家に帰ったんです。
And since I was busy, I went home without looking inside...
家に帰ったら…あの、部屋の明かりが…激しく明滅するんです。
When I got home... the lights in my room started flickering wildly.
で、パソコン立ち上げてメールの返信しようとしても…音声認識ソフトが立ち上がって他のアプリが開けないんです。
And even when I tried to turn on my PC to reply to emails... voice recognition software would launch and I couldn't open any other apps.
で、なんか気になってその…袋を開けたらこの子が出てきて、その瞬間にその現象が一気に止んだんです。
And feeling uneasy, I opened the bag, and this doll came out—and the moment I did, all those phenomena instantly stopped.
じゃあもう「早く出してくれ」っていうやつだったんですかね。
So it was probably saying, 'Let me out quickly!'
なんかメッセージをたぶん、もしからしたら…でもねめっっちゃ可愛い服まで着せて可愛がってますけど生きてますね田中さんは…w
It might have been sending a message... But you're dressing it in super cute clothes and doting on it, yet you're still alive, Tanaka-san...
可愛がってない？
Not that I'm not doting on it...
可愛がってないというか…敬ってます。
I respect it.
そこからちょっと物に…霊的な物とか魂みたいなものが宿るんじゃないかと思って…
That's when I started thinking that spiritual things or souls might dwell in objects...
現象が起きたときは怖くなかった？
Weren't you scared when those phenomena happened?
いやめちゃくちゃ怖いです。
No, I was extremely scared.
ちゃんと怖かったんだ！
You were genuinely scared!
なんかそういうの怖くないタイプなのかと思ってました。めちゃくちゃ怖いです。
I thought you were the type who wouldn't be scared of stuff like that. I'm terrified.
で、次ちょっと…最近…送られてきたというか、ものがあって、それ見てほしいんですけど…これなんですよ、これ。大量の…人形。
Now, next... recently... something was sent to me, and I want you to see it... This is it. A large amount of... dolls.
すごいね…あの、執着が…いやすごいなぁ…
Amazing... um, the obsession... Wow, that's intense...
「こんなにする？」っていうくらい、すごい遊び方してますね… これびゃ遊びじゃなくて… はい、遊びじゃないんだ…
Playing with them so harshly... 'Do you really have to go that far?' That's some intense way to play... This isn't play... Right, it's not play...
あの…姉妹…姉妹の妹が姉を呪ってた。ずーっと何年も。お姉ちゃんの事思って「死ね死ね死ね」と思ってずっと…
Um... sisters... A younger sister cursed her older sister. For years and years. Thinking of her older sister, thinking 'Die, die, die' the whole time...
実際この姉妹がどうなったかっていうと、姉の方が精神病院に入院したんですよ。
And what actually happened to these sisters? The older sister ended up hospitalized in a psychiatric ward.
で、結局妹も精神病院に入院して、二人とも入院してるんですよ。
And eventually, the younger sister was also hospitalized in a psychiatric ward. Both of them ended up in the hospital.
あれとかないですか？はあおさんは。呪いたい相手とかいないんですか？ 私が呪いたい相手？いないですね。
Don't you have anything like that, Haato-san? Isn't there anyone you want to curse? Someone I want to curse? There isn't.
だってほら、私が呪っちゃったら自分にも呪った分だけの対価を払わなきゃいけないから、そこまでしてやる必要はないかなって…
Because if I curse someone, I'd have to pay the price for it myself, so I don't think there's any need to go that far...
“返ってくる”っていうのはありますね。そう、返ってくるんだったらイヤです。
There is that 'it comes back to you' aspect. Yeah, if it comes back to me, I hate that.
だから…あの、クイックに呪えるやつありますよ。クイックに呪いを教えてくれるんだw
So... um, there's one where you can curse quickly. It teaches you how to curse quickly w
これとかは…呪ったりするんですか？田中さん。僕呪ったりしますから。
Does this... do you curse people with this, Tanaka-san? I do curse people.
誰呪うんですか？ w アンチをずっと呪ってます。そういうこと？
Who do you curse? w I've been continuously cursing antis. Is that so?
これは西アフリカの…あの呪術師が作ってくれたんですけど…どういう効果があるかって言ったら…これ…こう刺せるようになってるんですよね。穴が開いてて…ここに、その呪いたい相手の名前を言うと…
This was made by a West African... um, sorcerer... What kind of effect does it have? Well... you can stab it like this. There's a hole... and you say the name of the person you want to curse here...
名前だけでいいんだ。デスノートみたいなの。それでこう…おてがる…刺すと…そいつに不幸が訪れる… 気持ちもすっきりするし…
Just their name is fine? Like Death Note. And then... easily... when you stab it... misfortune visits that person. And you feel refreshed too...
あの、ちなみに…この部屋の中で一番呪力が強い呪物ってあるんですか？
Um, by the way... is there any cursed object with the strongest curse power in this room?
いや、あー…こんだけ集めてると…なんか増えててもわからない場合があるんですけど…
Well, ah... when you collect this many... sometimes you don't even know if something has increased...
確かに…あの最近…これどこからもらった…誰からからもらったのか、その…まったくわかんないぞっていう人形があるんですよ。
True... um, recently... there's a doll where I have no idea where or from whom I got it.
え、ちょっと見てもらえますか？ 見たいです、ぜひお願いします。すごい気持ち悪い人形なんですよ。
Eh, could you take a look at it? I want to see it, please! It's a super creepy doll.
気持ち悪いんだw はい、これなんですけどね。あれ w あれ、タランちゃま…？w
Creepy, huh w Yeah, this is it. Huh w Wait, Taran-chama...?
どういう人が作ったんですかね…
I wonder what kind of person made this...
これ私のお姉ちゃんが作ったやつ…これ
My older sister made this...
はあとさんのお姉ちゃんが作ったんですか…？
Haato-san's older sister made this...?
私のお姉ちゃんが作った…あのクモのね…
My older sister made... well, a spider...
あ、これがね？ そうそうそう。
Ah, this? Yeah, yeah, yeah.
体もクモになってるんですよ。
Its body is also a spider.
けっこうセンスありますよね。
It's got quite a sense of style.
いや、すごいですよね、これ。ぜひ置いておいてください。
Wow, this is amazing. Please leave it here.
あっ、いいんですか？
Ah, is that okay?
じゃあ置いておこうかな…
Then I guess I'll leave it here...
まあね、呪いはない気もするけど。
Well, I feel like there's no curse, but...
すごい馴染んでるw
It blends in so well.
やっぱり、（白が）なんもない人形もこういう場所に置いておけば
After all, if you put a plain doll in a place like this...
え、大丈夫ですか？私のお姉ちゃんが作ったんですけど、お姉ちゃん呪われちゃったりとかしません？
Eh, is it alright? My older sister made it, won't my sister get cursed?
お姉ちゃん作ってるだけなんで…あっそっか、そっか作ってたのか。私？あっ
Her sister's just making them... Ah right, right, she made it. Me? Ah
でもね、あの…これホンマにちょっと…
But you know, um... To be honest, this is a bit...
嫌な事言いますけど…
I'll say something unpleasant, but...
え、なんですか？
Eh, what is it?
あの…さっきから、はあとさんの後ろに…ずっと誰か居ますよね？あんま言いたくなかったんですけど…
Um... From a moment ago, someone's been right behind Haato-san all this time, right? I didn't really want to say it...
ずっと誰かついてきてますよ。
Someone's been following you the whole time.
え？
Eh?
待ったをかけた ちょっと考えた バカな女 まんまと引っかかった
I made you wait, thought about it a bit, and the foolish woman fell right into the trap.
だからどうした 自ら望んだと言ってんじゃん
So what? You're saying you wished for this yourself.
待ったをかけた ちょっと考えた
I made you wait, thought about it a bit,
少々ちょっと考えたから だからどうした
thought about it just a little bit, so so what?
お望み通りの末路ですわ！
This is the exact end you wished for!
なんて なんて なんて なんて なんて なんてなの
Why, why, why, why, why, why?
どうせつもり なんて なんて なんて なんて なんて なんた そんなもんか
That's how it's gonna be anyway. Why, why, why, why, why? Is that really all?
そういうもんか そういうもんだ きっとそうさ 違い無い
Is that how it is? That's how it is. Surely, there's no doubt.
まあ そういうもんか そういうもんだ きっとそうさ 絶対に
Well, is that how it is? That's how it is. Surely, absolutely.
そういうもんか そういうもんだ きっとそうさ 違い無い
Is that how it is? That's how it is. Surely, there's no doubt.
まあ そういうもんか そういうもんだ きっとそうさ 違い無いの
Well, is that how it is? That's how it is. Surely, there's no doubt.
違い無いよ 絶対
There's no doubt, absolutely.
待ったをかけた ちょっとためらった 確かにためらった
I made you wait, hesitated a bit, I definitely hesitated.
なんとかな なんとか気味こういうことではない
Somehow, somewhat hesitant, it's not like this.
待ったをかけた ちょっとためらった なんだなんだなんだなんだあなた
I made you wait, hesitated a bit, what, what, what, what are you?
だから だから こんなことは望んでないから
That's why, that's why, I never wished for something like this
なんて なんて なんて なんて なんて なんてなの どうせつもり なんて なんて なんて なんて なんて
Why, why, why, why, why, why? That's how it's gonna be anyway. Why, why, why, why, why?
黙って私に従って 黙って私に従って 黙って私に従って 従え 従え 従って
Shut up and obey me, shut up and obey me, shut up and obey me, obey, obey, obey
君に一切の拒否権無いよ
You have no right of refusal whatsoever.
黙って従って 黙って私に従って 従え 従え 従って お願い お願い お願い お願い
Shut up and obey, shut up and obey me, obey, obey, obey, please, please, please, please
黙って私に従って 黙って私に従って 従え 従え 従え 従え 従え 従えって言ってんの
Shut up and obey me, shut up and obey me, obey, obey, obey, obey, obey, I told you to obey!
黙って私に従って 黙って私に従って 従え 従え 従って お願い お願い お願い お願い お願い お願い お願い お願い
Shut up and obey me, shut up and obey me, obey, obey, obey, please, please, please, please, please, please, please, please
お願い お願い お願い
Please, please, please
ということで、ソロメちゃんに来てもらったよー！
And so, we invited Sorome-chan here!
位置中、100戦、満点ソロメ！
Position-chu, 100 battles, perfect score Sorome!
皆様方を100万点笑顔にさせますわ！
I will make everyone's smiles 1 million points!
今はまだ一般人、いつかお嬢様に成りたい！
Right now I'm still a commoner, but someday I want to become a lady!
そして今日は、はあと様をお祝いしに来ました！
And today, I came to celebrate Haato-sama!
100万点ハモらせるでございますわ！
I will make the harmony 1 million points!
はあとさまぁー！来てくれてありがとうー！
Haato-samaaa! Thank you for coming!
どくず一緒に歌えてすごく嬉しい！歌ってみたら本当に最高でした！
I'm so happy we could sing Dozukuzu together! Singing it together was truly amazing!
普段お上品なソロメちゃんのヤンデレ感がたまらなかったです！
The yandere vibe from usually refined Sorome-chan was irresistible!
歌声も喋り方も性格も、好きです！
I love your singing voice, your way of speaking, and your personality!
わっ
Wha-
おっ
O-
はあとさま本当…ありがとうございますわ！こちらこそ！
Haato-sama really... thank you so much! Same here!
なんかこうやって、あの…縁が繋がって、こうやって今一緒に歌歌えたのがすごく嬉しいですわ。
I'm so happy that through our bonds connecting like this, we were able to sing together right now.
もうすごい、もう私ものはあとさまのこと全部可愛いと思ってるし、もう本当に…
It's amazing, I think everything about Haato-sama is so cute, and really...
うん…可愛い！
Yeah... Cute!
おめでとう今日は本当にありがとうございました！こちらこそありがとう！
Congratulations today, thank you so much! Thank you too!
じゃあ、さようならまったねー！まったねー！
Well then, goodbye, see you later! See you later!
ようこそお越しなすったご主人様 隣に座らせーの 萌え萌え萌え萌え
Welcome, honored master who has come from afar. Sit next to me, moe moe moe moe
こんなんで誰が喜ぶのさ ねぇ教えて 笑顔で up pull pull
Who's even happy with something like this? Hey tell me, with a smile, up pull pull
愛想を忘れてご苦労様 私とあなたでせーの luv luv luv luv
Forget your friendliness, good work. You and me, ready, luv luv luv luv
こんなんで誰が喜ぶのさ ねぇ教えて
Who's even happy with something like this? Hey tell me
ようこそ お越し なさった ご主人様
Welcome, Master, who has come.
愛想忘れて ご苦労様
Good work forgetting your friendliness.
私とあなたで せーの
You and me together, ready, go!
luv luv luv luv
こんなんで誰が喜ぶのさ
Who in the world could be happy with this?
ねえ 教えて 笑顔で up pull pull
Hey, tell me, with a smile, up pull pull!
ひらり はらり 女の子
Fluttering, drifting, a little girl.
ふわり ふわり 言葉の saw
Floating, drifting, the saw of words.
それってつまり お冷みな娘
In other words, a cold young lady.
感情的リアル 笑顔で up pull pull
Emotionally real, with a smile, up pull pull!
人は見かけによらぬもの
Appearances can be deceiving.
嘘は嘘だと見抜けない
You can't tell a lie from a lie.
したたかな袖 裾の革
Tough sleeves, leather at the hem.
鳥肌 鵞毛肌 アンドゥトロワ
Goosebumps, gooseneck skin, un deux trois.
間違ったご指名 をいただきます
Sorry for the wrong appointment, but I'll take it.
私とあなたで せーの
You and me together, ready, go!
luv luv luv luv
これはド派手にご苦労様
Good work on this extravagant display!
遊びましょう 笑顔で up pull pull
Let's play, with a smile, up pull pull!
ひらり はらり ここは何処
Fluttering, drifting, where is this?
ふわり ふわり 掃討 let me show
Floating, drifting, sweeping, let me show.
それってつまり お冷みな娘
In other words, a cold young lady.
確証的リアル 笑顔で up pull pull
Confirmatory real, with a smile, up pull pull!
歌い出す秘密の鐘
The secret bell starts to ring out.
終わることのないこの世界
This world that never ends.
悲しい子供は
Sad children...
虚しい子供は 眠らせて
Empty children, let them sleep.
お家事 ごっこ 遊びましょう
Playing house, let's play.
悲しい子供は
Sad children...
虚しい子供は 眠らせて
Empty children, let them sleep.
眠らせて
Let them sleep...
そのままごと遊びましょう 笑顔で up pull pull
Let's play house just like this, with a smile, up pull pull!
ひらり はらり 女の子
Fluttering, drifting, a little girl.
ふわり ふわり 言葉の saw
Floating, drifting, the saw of words.
それってつまり お冷みな娘
In other words, a cold young lady.
感情的リアル 笑顔で up pull pull
Emotionally real, with a smile, up pull pull!
遊びましょう 笑顔で up pull pull
Let's play, with a smile, up pull pull!
up pull pull
お疲れ様！
Good job!
誕生日おめでとう！歌ってくれて！
Happy birthday! Thank you for singing!
なんとね、2021年の4年ぶりに歌ってくれました！
Amazingly, she sang this for the first time in 4 years since 2021!
チューリングラブってさ、覚えてる？覚えてるよ、4年前に！
Do you remember Turing Love? I remember, 4 years ago!
そう、誕生日おめでとうってね、若かった！
Yes, "Happy birthday," she said—we were so young!
え、今はなんか違う？若くない？いや、でもクールになったんだよね。
Eh, are you different now? Not young? Well, but you got cooler, right?
私たち今日、ねえ、クール可愛かったもんね。
Today, you know, we were pretty cool and cute.
確かにね、いつものチューリングラブこんなことしてたよね？
True, in the usual Turing Love we did stuff like this, right?
なんか、あの、お互いとかさ、なんかこんなことしてたのに...
Like, pointing at each other and stuff like that...
今日クールになりました。
Today we became cool.
どうしたの？
What's wrong?
自由すぎるだろ！
You're too free-spirited!
写真とか、あ、そうね、あの、今日歌ったモエチャッカファイアもね、歌ってみたも出したので、ぜひ見てください！
Photos and—ah, right, today we also sang "Moe Chakkaka Fire," and we released a cover of it, so please check it out!
え、なんでこの曲にしてくれたんですか？
Eh, why did you choose this song?
えー、これ歌いたかった！やっぱね、歌ってみたも出したし、せっかくだからね、一緒に歌いたいなと思って選びました。
Uh, I wanted to sing this! After all, we released a cover, and since we have the chance, I wanted us to sing it together, so I chose it.
なんか意外な選曲だった、この時ね！
It felt like a surprisingly unexpected song choice at the time!
え、なんか、これ今回ホラーライブがテーマなんだけど。
Eh, like, the theme this time is a horror live, though.
そんなコンセプトのライブ見たことない！
I've never seen a live with that kind of concept!
で、なんか、あ、いいかなと思って。
And I thought, ah, this might be good.
あー、なるほどね！ちょっとね、落とし込んでね。
Ah, I see! We kind of incorporated it.
なんか一緒に写真とか撮る？撮りたい！
Shall we take a picture together or something? I want to!
ってか、すごいマジで！ライブステージ、ねえ！めちゃくちゃ可愛い！
I mean, seriously! The live stage, hey! It's so cute!
なんか、いいポーズ。やりたいポーズある？
Some nice pose. Is there a pose you want to do?
え、まず、まず普通に、まずね。イェーイ！
Eh, first, just normally, first. Yay!
パシャ、パシャ。え、可愛い！可愛いってことでしょう。
Snap, snap. Eh, cute! That must mean it's cute.
あと、あと、ハート、ハート？ハート作っとく？
And, and, heart, heart? Should we make a heart?
いい感じ！いい感じ！よっし。
Feels good! Feels good! Alright.
次、次、次。あと、え？
Next, next, next. And, eh?
あと何だろう、なんかデカくね？あ、これこれ、これ、これこれ。
What else, isn't it big? Ah, this, this, this, this.
やだ！で、感じだね。あれは4年前にもさ、撮ったさ、ちょっと座ってさ、お嬢様みたいな。
No way! And, it's like that. We took one 4 years ago too—sitting down, like young ladies.
こっちじゃない？こっちじゃね？カメラの方を向いてね。
Isn't it this way? Face the camera.
ああ、いい！いいじゃん！4年前もこれで撮ったんだよ！みんな見てる！
Ah, nice! That's great! We took it like this 4 years ago too! Everyone's watching!
久しぶりの！衣装も変わってね！本当なんだよね、二人とも衣装変わった！
Long time no see! The outfits changed too! Truly, both of our outfits changed!
めちゃくちゃ可愛い、その衣装！欲しくもめちゃくちゃ足、これでは足的に向けたね、一応ね。
Super cute, that outfit! I wanted it so much—our legs, pointing towards our feet, just in case.
え、これ、私は結構隠してるけど
Eh, I'm actually hiding quite a bit, but...
この足を、てか隠してるのが逆にいいんだって。
For this leg—well, that it's hidden is actually better, you know.
あ、そういうこと。
Ah, is that so?
ちぐらみえのね、分かってまえな。
It's just slightly visible, you see. I see.
この、あれだもんね。
Because of this thing, right?
衣装が、やばい、衣装が、やばい！
The costume is crazy, the costume is crazy!
だいぶ攻めた衣装じゃなかったよ。
That wasn't a very bold costume, was it?
絶対領域がね。もう。よーし。
The absolute territory... Man. Alright!
どう？なんかセクシーポーズとかしなくて大丈夫？
How is it? Shouldn't we do a sexy pose or something?
セクシーポーズ？したいの？
A sexy pose? Do you want to do one?
大丈夫かな？いや、大丈夫です！おめでとう！
Will it be okay? No, it's fine! Happy birthday!
いやいや、ありがとう！
No, no, thank you!
またね、なんか一緒に歌って踊りたい！
I'd love to sing and dance together again!
うん。
Yeah.
踊ろう、ぜひ。
Let's dance, absolutely.
是非ともまた次も踊りましょう！嬉しい！大満足！
Let's definitely dance together next time too! Yay! So satisfying!
じゃあ、バイバーイ！
Well then, bye-bye!
バイバーイ！頑張ってね！ありがとう！バイバーイ！
Bye-bye! Do your best! Thank you! Bye-bye!
ありがとう！バイバーイ！
Thank you! Bye-bye!
正しくなれない 霧がどこを見た
I can't become righteous. Where did the fog look?
片っ端から 確かめたくて
Wanting to check everything from one end,
描き続けたい 偽りで
Wanting to keep painting with falsehoods,
出会えた僕らは 何一つも
The us who met each other haven't had
奪われてないから
a single thing taken away from us.
正しくなれない
I can't become righteous.
僕ら育ってくみたい
It seems we are growing up,
愛されるみたい 暖かい波を読む
seeming to be loved, reading the warm waves.
今日 今を選ぶ
Choosing today, choosing now.
濁った浅瀬色 尋ねる声で 何度でも
In muddy shallow waters, with a probing voice, no matter how many times,
僕ら 嘘つきだね 両思いだね
we are liars, aren't we? Our feelings are mutual, aren't they?
枯れ果てるまで 泣き笑い 今日を受け入れてく
Until we wither away, crying and laughing, accepting today,
喜び合った日々を 忘れはしないけど
I won't forget the days we shared our joy, but...
知らない方が幸せだって 知れば 知り得るほど
The more I learn that ignorance is bliss, the more I come to know it,
正しくなれない 霧がどこを見た
I can't become righteous. Where did the fog look?
片っ端から 確かめたくて
Wanting to check everything from one end,
描き続けたい 偽りで出会えた
wanting to keep painting with falsehoods, the us who met
僕らは 何一つも 奪われてないから
haven't had a single thing taken away from us.
今 心閉ざさぬように
Now, so as not to close our hearts,
少しずつちゃんと暮れを続けよう 枯れ木に笑顔だけ
let's keep giving step by step, just a smile to the withered trees...
君の肉体も心も 全て濁り無くさせないよ ねぇ
I won't let your body and heart become completely untarnished—hey,
知れば 知り得るほど 幸せだって たどり着いてもいい
The more I know, the more I realize happiness—it's okay to reach it.
君だけが見る 色だけの鏡 僕でも いつか分かる日まで
Until the day even I can understand the mirror of only colors you see,
描き続けたい 偽りで出会えた 雫
wanting to keep painting with falsehoods, droplets...
生る枝分かれるよ 導かれ
being born and branches splitting, guided...
大したもんじゃない 無駄なもんじゃない 幸せのりを
It's nothing special, it's not useless. The glue of happiness...
寛大にしてくように
to make generous...
ずっと ずっと 砕かれようが 折れない 砂の穴
always, always, even if crushed, unbreakable sand holes...
可能性が 広げる縄場 可能性を 諦められないから 笑う
Expanding the rope of possibilities, because I can't give up on possibilities, I smile.
正しくなれない 霧がどこを見た
I can't become righteous. Where did the fog look?
片っ端から 確かめたくて
Wanting to check everything from one end,
描き続けたい 偽りで出会えた
wanting to keep painting with falsehoods, the us who met
僕らは 何一つも
haven't had a single thing
全て 嫌われても 奪われてないから
taken away from us, even if hated by everyone.
はっとちゃん！
Haato-chan!
大好きだよ！
I love you so much!
ちょっ…
Wait...
はっちゃも！
Hacchama!
私も大好き！
I love you too!
「どこまで？」「ごめんね」「ごめんね、なさい」
"How far?" "I'm sorry." "I'm sorry."
「いなくなって、寂しかったよ。」
"When you disappeared, I was so lonely."
「いつもそばにいるって、言ったじゃん。」
"You said you'd always be by my side, didn't you?"
「ずっと待ってたよ。」
"I waited for you the whole time."
おっ？
Oh?
はあと？
Haato?
はあとちゃん、はあとちゃん、はあとだよ！
Haato-chan, Haato-chan, it's Haato!
こうやって会話するの初めてだよね！
This is the first time we've talked like this!
さっき歌ってた感想、最高だったよ！ありがとう！
Your singing just now was amazing! Thank you!
なんか大人っぽくなったね！
You seem kind of grown-up!
実は最近旅をすることが増えまして、
Actually, recently I've been traveling more,
そこで新しい自分を見つけて、ちょっぴり大人っぽい曲にチャレンジしてみました！
and found a new me there, so I tried challenging myself with a somewhat mature song!
はあ、特に好きな歌詞とかはある？
Haa, are there any lyrics you especially like?
はい！もう一度もう一度とも何回も思ったでしょう、という歌詞がありまして、
Yes! There's a lyric that goes, "How many times did I think 'once more, once more'?"
出会った景色や人の温もりを思いながら、すごく感情移入しました！
Thinking of the scenery and warmth of the people I met, I really got into it!
おお、そうなんだ！今日リリース予定なので、みんなもたくさん聞いてね！
Oh, is that right? It's scheduled for release today, so everyone listen to it a lot!
そしてぜひ！上手に正しくなれない歌ったよ！どうだった？
And please! I sang "I can't become properly good"! How was it?
今までの記憶とか葛藤を振り返りながらでね、すごく心に染みましたね！
Looking back on memories and conflicts up until now, it really soaked into my heart!
ほんとだよ！はあとちゃんはさ、ずっと塞ぎ込んでで、全然はあとちゃんの話耳も傾けないでさ！
That's right! Haato-chan, you were shut away the whole time, and wouldn't lend an ear to Haato-chan's talk at all!
そんなことないけど…
That's not true...
ごめんね。でも、お互い知り合って分かり合えたから、よかったなって思うよ！
Sorry. But since we got to know and understand each other, I think it's for the best!
おお、ならいっか！
Oh, then I guess it's fine!
そんなふたりの家族写真も今回は撮ってもらいました！
We also had a family photo of the two of us taken this time!
イェーイ！
Yay!
ふたりの仲良しの証！ビートルズペストリーになっております！
Proof of our close friendship! It's a Beatles tapestry!
おしゃれだ！
How stylish!
じゃあみんな行くよ！せーの！グッズグッズゲットしてください！
Well everyone, here we go! Ready, set! Please get the goods!
ねえ 見て お気に入りの
Hey, look, my favorite
世界に一つの お人形さん
one and only doll in the world.
顔も性格も 違ったけど
Our faces and personalities were different,
ずっとみんな 仲よし
but everyone's always get along.
苦しいを 傍えたとき 私にもできた恩返し
When suffering was near, I too could return the favor.
大事な人 好きな人
Important person, the one I love,
いつもそばにいてほしい、よね。
I want you always by my side, you know.
上手く縫ってね 私にしてくれたように
Sew me up well, just like you did for me.
少しほつれたとことか
Even where it frayed a bit,
めちゃ可愛いね
it's super cute.
身体もたくさん 好きにつなぎ合わせて
Connecting my body together however you like,
少し歪だけどね
though it's a bit crooked.
大切な 家族たち なの
You're my precious family.
ねえ 見て お気に入りの
Hey, look, my favorite
世界に一つの お人形さん
one and only doll in the world.
顔も性格も 違ったけど
Our faces and personalities were different,
ずっとみんな 仲よし
but everyone's always get along.
仲よし 仲よし 仲よし 仲よし
Close friends, close friends...
やさしい、うれしい、たのしい、いとおしい、
Gentle, happy, fun, beloved,
ほめて、なでて、
praise me, pet me,
ねえ、ねえ、ねえ、ねえ、ねえ...
hey, hey, hey...
上手く縫ってね 私にしてくれたように
Sew me up well, just like you did for me.
少しほつれたとことか
Even where it frayed a bit,
めちゃ可愛いね
it's super cute.
身体もたくさん 好きにつなぎ合わせて 少し歪だけどね
Connecting my body together however you like, though it's a bit crooked.
大切な。大切な。大切な。大切な。大切な。大切な。
Precious... Precious...
お人形
Doll
生誕ライブ限定グッズ販売のお知らせ!!
Birthday live limited merchandise announcement!!
家族写真B2タペストリー
Family Photo B2 Tapestry
ゴージャスな額縁風デザインと肖像画のようなふたりがとってもキュート。
Gorgeous frame-style design and portraitsof the two of them looking super cute.
お部屋の壁に、今日の思い出を飾って彩り豊かな推し活ができちゃいます!
Hang today's memories on your room walland enjoy a colorful oshi-katsu!
おでかけちゃまぬいぐるみ
Outing-Chama Plushie
ボタン風の目がとっても可愛いぬいぐるみ。丁寧にひとつひとつ再現された
A very cute plushie with button-like eyes.Faithfully and meticulously recreated
ドレス衣装のちゃまと一緒におでかけして旅に出れちゃいます!
dress outfit, you can go on a triptogether with Chama!
鞄に付けられるハートチャーム付き!
Comes with a heart charm for your bag!
タランちゃまぬいぐるみポーチ
Taran-Chama Plushie Pouch
あの…タランちゃまがポーチに!?背中のファスナーが開いて
That... Taran-Chama is a pouch!?The zipper on the back opens
収納できる便利アイテム。ゴスロリ衣装のタランちゃまが可愛すぎる!
for convenient storage.Taran-Chama in gothic lolita is too cute!
チェーンがついているから安心して外にお散歩させられるよ!
It has a chain so you can safelytake her out for a walk!
タランちゃますまほリング
Taran-Chama Smartphone Ring
スマホの落下は「タランちゃま」にお任せ!しっかり張り付いて守ってくれます!
Leave phone drops to "Taran-Chama"!It sticks firmly to protect your phone!
愛くるしいお目目と、つい目が合っちゃう瞬間も癒やされてたまりません。
You'll be endlessly healed by her adorable eyesand those moments when your eyes meet.
全部セットは数量限定もあります!
Full sets also have a limited quantity version!
フルセット購入特典の数量限定バージョンは、箔押し複製メッセージ入りポストカードと
The limited quantity full-set bonus includesa foil-stamped duplicated message postcard
赤井はあと直筆サイン、特典ボイス「ひみつの話」もあるよ!
with Akai Haato's facsimile signature,and a bonus voice "Secret Talk"!
特典カードもあるよ!
There's also a bonus card!
hololive公式ECサイトへGO!!2025/8/10 ~ 2025/9/16
Go to the hololive official EC site!!2025/8/10 ~ 2025/9/16